Kontakt

www.linkedin.com/in/rebekka-rueth (LinkedIn)

Top-Kenntnisse

Fashion
Communication
Sustainability

Languages

Deutsch (Native or Bilingual)
Englisch (Native or Bilingual)
Französisch (Full Professional)
Spanisch (Limited Working)
Schwedisch (Limited Working)

Publications

"Interpretating for Europe"

Rebekka Rüth

Fashion & Textile Enthusiast @ Südwesttextil | #30u30 Crew 2020 | Podcasterin "Textil für Morgen"
Stuttgart

Zusammenfassung

[she / her / textilerin]

I'm a people passionate, open-minded fashion & textile enthusiast. Creative at heart, passionate in communication and mindful about the wellbeing of people and the planet. Inspired by the smallest and the most beautiful things in life. Art and fashion. Cultures and languages. People and the power of collaboration and networks.

Sustainability. With a focus on the textile and fashion industry, I have set my mind, projects and research on making a change through collaboration. Looking at the UN SDGs I feel that SDG17 Partnership for the Goals will be the crucial step for industries and nations to challenge the Paris Agenda.

Fashion. My fascination for fashion and textile products goes back to my early childhood sewing my first pieces with my grandma. In the meantime my passion for products and the industry has developed and grown with living in Paris, Sweden and Switzerland, focusing on communication, PR, branding, digital transformation, leadership and sustainability in the industry and beyond.

Networks. Growing up in a small town and multigenerational environment taught me the value of supporting others and relying on a good network. Moving on to more international and professional contexts, I'm dedicated to creating value, connecting people and communicating in networks.

Berufserfahrung

Südwesttextil e.V. 4 Jahre 5 Monate

Leiterin Kommunikation, Event & Nachhaltigkeit März 2022 - Present (1 Monat)

Page 1 of 3

Stuttgart, Baden-Württemberg, Deutschland

Referentin Projekte, Nachhaltigkeit & Kommunikation Oktober 2020 - Februar 2022 (1 Jahr 5 Monate)

Stuttgart, Baden-Württemberg, Deutschland

Junior-Referentin Projekte, Nachhaltigkeit & Kommunikation September 2018 - September 2020 (2 Jahre 1 Monat)

Stuttgart und Umgebung, Deutschland

Werkstudentin Projekte Kommunikation + Event November 2017 - August 2018 (10 Monate)

Stuttgart Area, Germany

Gesamtverband der deutschen Textil- und Modeindustrie e.V.

Go Textile! Botschafterin

August 2016 - Dezember 2017 (1 Jahr 5 Monate)

https://www.go-textile.de/team

OUTLETCITY METZINGEN GmbH - ein Unternehmen der HOLY AG

Sales Promoter

April 2016 - März 2017 (1 Jahr)

Stuttgart und Umgebung, Deutschland

HOLY FASHION GROUP

Intern Brand Coordination Strellson

August 2016 - Februar 2017 (7 Monate)

Mercedes- Benz Fashion Week

Volunteer

Januar 2016 - Januar 2016 (1 Monat)

Schülerhilfe GmbH & Co.KG

Teacher

Oktober 2014 - August 2015 (11 Monate)

Stadt Altena

Marketing Intern

Juli 2014 - August 2014 (2 Monate)

Christian Dior Couture

Internship

Juni 2012 - Juni 2012 (1 Monat)

Stage d'obervation d'une semaine dans le département maille.

Ausbildung

Hochschule Reutlingen

Master of Science - MS, Textile Chain Research · (2018 - 2020)

Hochschule Reutlingen

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Fashion Management (International Fashion Retail) · (2014 - 2018)

Högskolan i Borås

Textile Management · (2015 - 2016)

Max-Planck-Gymnasium

High School · (2012 - 2014)

Lycée International de Saint-Germain-en-Laye

High School · (2011 - 2012)